國土安全
第三季 第十一集
美國空軍及海軍
Air and naval forces of the United States
對恐怖組織發起了一系列攻擊
launched a series of strikes against terrorist facilities...
泛美航空103號班機于洛克比失事
Pan Am flight 103 crashed into the town of Lockerbie.
他已批準在非洲  歐洲和中東的恐怖行動
He has sanctioned acts of terror in Africa, Europe, the Middle East.
我們不容科威特遭受侵略
This will not stand, this aggression against Kuwait.
對于恐怖襲擊的不懈打擊
This relentless pursuit of terror.
我們將一視同仁
We will make no distinction...
美國軍艦科爾號
The USS Cole was attacked
在亞丁灣港口加油時遭到襲擊
while refueling in the port of Aden.
這是恐怖主義行動
This was an act of terrorism.
這是可鄙懦弱的行動
It was a despicable and cowardly act.
下面為您演奏的
The next samba we're going to swing for you
是一首經典曲目
is one of the good old favorites.
直到他受到了阻擊
...until something stops him.
整個事件就發生在我的眼前
It was right in front of my eyes,
而我絲毫沒預料到
and I never saw it coming.
該飛機撞向了世貿中心
That plane crashed into the World Trade Center.
成千上萬的民眾東奔西逃
Thousands of people running.
我們必須  也將在國內外保持警惕
We must and we will remain vigilant at home and abroad.
你是我見過最聰明
You're the smartest and the dumbest fucking person
又最愚蠢的人
I've ever known.
我不是不明真相的那個人
I'm not the one who got it wrong.
我是唯一的明白人
I'm the only one who got it right.
拿下
Take 'em.
通通拿下
Take 'em all.
《國土安全》前情提要
Previously on Homeland:
索爾  我以為你今晚不回來了
Saul, I didn't expect you back tonight.
這位是阿倫·伯納德
This is Alain Bernard.
阿倫·伯納德承認自己是以色列情報人員
Alain Bernard admitted to being an asset of Israeli intelligence.
把他丟進地洞里關著去
Put him in a dark fucking hole.
現在我們來說說納賽爾·赫佳茲
It's time we talk about Nasser Hejazi,
你用這個名字從革命衛隊中挪用了4500萬美元
whose name you used to embezzle more than $45 million.
你現在成了自己國家的敵人
You are now an enemy of your own state.
我已經為你計劃好了
I got plans for you.
什么計劃
What plans?
我要把你放回伊朗
I'm gonna play you back into Iran.
從現在起  你為我們做事
From now on, you work for us.
我設了個局
I have a play.
牽涉到了布洛迪
It involves Brody.
你有什么好主意
What's your big idea?
達尼什·阿克巴里
Danesh Akbari.
伊朗革命衛隊的首領
Head of Iran's Revolutionary Guard.
對
Right.
賈瓦迪的上司
Javadi's boss.
布洛迪能接觸到他
Brody can get to him.
他們送我至邊境處
The guys get me to the border
然后我示意投降
where I surrender myself?
沒錯
Correct.
發生了什么事
What just happen?
火力太猛了
We are under heavy fire!
撤退  撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
我不撤退
I'm not going back.
這件事你一個人做不到
You can't do this by yourself.
我距離邊界不到三百米了  卡莉
I'm 300 yards from the border, Carrie!
我能完成任務
I can make it!
你會死在那里的
You will die over there!
不  你錯了  卡莉
No, you're wrong, Carrie!
因為你會來帶我回去
'Cause you're gonna get me home!
不  不準那么說
No, don't say that!
不要把壓力強加給我  那簡直是白日夢
Do not put that on me! It's a fantasy!
你會想出辦法的  我對你有信心
You'll find a way. I have faith.
我是尼古拉斯·布洛迪
...Nicholas Brody.
我因為中情局爆炸事件被美國通緝
[波斯語]
布洛迪成功越境了
Brody made it across.
你呢  索爾
And you, Saul,
還依舊身在局中
are still in the game.
我會下地獄的
I'll be damned.
你在德黑蘭有個叔叔
You have an uncle in Tehran.
-讓我們倆單獨待一會  -是  長官
- Give us a few minutes. - Yes, sir.
他們每天讓我放一小時的風
They let me out one hour a day.
鍛煉身體
To exercise.
那個房間就比這里大一丁點
In a room that's... three feet bigger than this.
你竊取我們的情報  就只能受這種待遇
Well, you spy on us, that's what you get.
我不是間諜
I'm not a spy.
我們當場抓獲了你
Well, we caught you red-handed.
你是抓到我跟你老婆偷情
You caught me with your wife.
你最好別跟我對著干
You don't want to be antagonizing me,
畢竟我是來放你出去的
not when I'm here to get you out.
你想讓我干什么
What do you want?
我有項任務正在實施
I have an operation in progress.
在德黑蘭
In Tehran.
那項任務的支援隊伍已被迫撤離
Support team for that operation was forced to pull out.
摩薩德在當地安插有特工
Mossad has agents on the ground there.
我需要兩名特工
I need two of them.
你可以自己問特拉維夫要
You can ask Tel Aviv yourself.
他們會問許多有關任務的問題
Well, they'd ask a lot of questions about the mission,
我沒準備好要回答
questions I'm not prepared to answer.
-但就算我找人也沒什么區別  -最好有區別
- But it won't be any different if I ask. - It better be.
因為我現在跟你這個干了我老婆的滑頭啰嗦
'Cause it's the only reason I'm standing here talking
就是為了讓你辦成這件事
to the greaseball who fucked my wife.
沒人希望讓你待在這里
No one wants you here.
摩薩德不想  我也不想
Not Mossad, not me.
彼此幫個忙
Do everyone a favor.
把事做成
Make this happen.
阿布·納齊爾生前幫我安排了逃跑路線
Abu Nazir arranged my escape route for me.
我從哈利法克斯藏進一艘貨船的集裝箱
I left Halifax in a container on a freighter.
去了哥倫比亞
It took me to Columbia.
又被輛吉普車拉到委內瑞拉
There I was taken by Jeep to Venezuela.
過境時出了些麻煩
There was trouble at the border.
-所以遭到了槍擊  -誰開的槍
- That's when I was shot. - By?
不知道  想領賞的人吧
I don't know. Someone trying to collect the reward.
然后呢
And then?
都告你了
I told you.
他們
They...
他們把我弄到了加拉加斯
they took me to Caracas.
那棟爛尾樓
To this... slum.
你就是在那里變成癮君子的
Where you became an addict.
什么  不  不是
What? Wait. No. No.
我中了槍
I was shot.
這里  還有這里
Here and here.
他們用海洛因給我止痛
They used heroin on me for the pain.
是很難戒  但我戒了
It wasn't easy to stop, but I did.
-用了多久  -沒多久
- How long did that take? - A while.
-有艾滋嗎  -沒有
- Do you have AIDS? - No.
檢查過嗎
Have you been tested?
咱們扯這些干嘛
Why are we even talking about this?
我沒艾滋
I don't have AIDS.
我離開加拉加斯是不想死在那里
I left Caracas because I was gonna die there.
有個伊瑪目幫我逃出來的
An Imam helped me get out,
到了伊朗這里  我就是想避難
get here to Iran, and I just want asylum.
真不理解你們干嘛這么折磨我
I don't understand why you're giving me such a hard time.
你覺得這就是我們要做的事情嗎
Is that what you think we're doing?
就是為了折磨你嗎
Giving you a hard time?
我已經
I've...
趕了這么遠的路
I've traveled so far,
還險些死在路上  我是想
and I almost didn't make it, and I just thought...
到了這邊就安全了  還以為
I just thought I'd be safe here. I just...
能受到些禮遇
I just thought I'd be welcome.
憑什么
Why?
憑我做的事
Because of what I did.
端了中情局
Bombed Langley.
他們的核心啊
Their heart.
你想什么呢
You think what?
我們會歡迎叛國者嗎
We like traitors here?
不是
No.
-誰派你來的  -沒人  都告訴你了
- Who sent you? - No one. I told you.
我就是想避難
I just want asylum.
就是想...想歇歇
I just w... want rest.
要休息一下嗎
Should we take a break?
太好了  拜托
Yes. Please. Please.
不行
No.
再過一遍
Go over it again.
女士專用的士  叫車專線:1821
[法語]
謝謝
Merci.
[法語]
-你好  -你好
- Bonjour. - Bonjour.
[法語]
女士
Madame?
您收好
Voilà
翻譯：餓得慌  zhanginfo  肉松  幸田實果子
■
翻譯：丁小七  川川  葉子  慕秋雪
校對：wdjmhs  zhanginfo  慕秋雪    時間軸：紫熏   憑陵新月
■
后期：餓得慌    監制：wdjmhs
謝謝
Merci.
謝謝您  女士
Merci pour vous, madame.
他們要您上去
可以等等嗎  十分鐘后我有個會
阿克巴里將軍找您呢  先生
[阿拉伯語]
馬蘇德·施拉吉
Masud Sherazi?
你是
Yes?
我是你侄女的朋友
I'm a friend of your niece.
你有東西要交給我吧
You have something for me.
東西呢
Where is it?
先說說是怎么回事
First you tell me what's going on.
法拉怎么和你說的
What did Fara say to you?
她要我幫個忙
That she needed a favor.
出于對你的保護  你知道這些就可以了
For your own protection, that's all you want to know.
這也算是保護我嗎
And was this for my protection?
從海關走私違禁物  還送到我家里
Sending contraband through customs, here to my house?
-東西沒走海關  -上面寫著呢
- It never went through customs. - It says!
不是  那是我們的標簽
No, those are our labels.
從日內瓦發的外交包裹
It came by diplomatic pouch from Geneva.
你是中情局的吧
You're CIA, aren't you?
我是你侄女的朋友
I'm a friend of your niece's.
那她也是中情局的了
So she's CIA, too.
為她祖國的敵對國工作
Working against her own country.
是為她的祖國工作
Working for her country.
她相信你理解這點
She trusted you to underand that.
她讓我把這個給你
She asked me to give you this.
她在美國也戴頭巾嗎
She wears the hijab there in America?
我覺得她的心還在這里
I think her heart is here still,
還在德黑蘭
in Tehran.
那我的兄弟
And my brother,
他同意她這么做嗎
does he approve what she's doing?
我認為他逐漸接受了
My understanding is he's grown to accept it.
謝謝
Thank you.
告訴我  你還需要什么
Tell me, is there anything else you need?
你相信他只是來避難的嗎
我們仍在核查他那番話
那你相信他嗎
不確定
有人出現在邊境  我們得多加小心
你對他太溫和了
我知道
如果你真有疑慮...
我覺得他在這是客  是貴賓
可能有巨大的宣傳價值
這個炸了中情局的人嗎
他是炸了中情局的美國士兵
過去式的美國"英雄"
他這輩子算是受盡磨難了
我覺得不該再折磨他了
我們得確認可以相信他
然后才能讓全世界知道他在這
是的  長官
[波斯語]
我提個建議如何
也許你該和布洛迪面談  由您親自判斷
這是要事  值得考慮
-拿到手機了嗎  -是
- You got the phone? - Yeah.
她叔叔怎么樣
How was the uncle?
開始有疑慮  后來沒事了
He was dodgy at first, then okay.
你那邊情況如何
How did you make out?
阿倫說通了摩薩德的人
Alain got Mossad to say yes.
很好
Good.
給你安排了兩名特工準備見你
I have two agents on the ground there ready to meet you.
都是伊朗籍的
Both Iranian nationals.
他們知道多少
What do they know?
我盡可能少告訴他們
I told everyone as little as possible.
你來決定告訴他們多少
You need to decide how much to let them in.
我跟他們說了
I did tell them
他們參與的是近距離暗殺行動
they'll be supporting a close-quarters assassination,
你需要一把武器
and that you'll be needing a weapon.
希望第一次見面他們能有些方案
Expect them to bring some options to the first meeting.
我想把見面安排在法拉叔叔家
I'd like to make it at the uncle's house.
你確定嗎
You sure?
確定
Yeah.
那里很安全  我相信他
It's safe there. I trust him.
現在你賓館有衛星監控
I got a satellite over your hotel right now.
我在七樓陽臺上
I'm on the balcony-- seventh floor.
你是不是包著頭巾
Is that a head scarf you're wearing?
你開玩笑的  是吧
You're kidding, right?
看得見個鬼
I can't see crap.
太暗了
It's too dark.
賈瓦迪那還沒什么消息
We haven't heard much from Javadi,
應該算是件好事
but we're taking that as a good thing.
他們把布洛迪藏在阿扎迪塔附近了
They got Brody stashed at a compound near Azadi Tower.
顯然他在努力撐著
Apparently, he's holding together.
還不錯
Well enough anyway.
熬過了整整三天的審訊
He survived three solid days of interrogations.
卡莉
Carrie?
怎么了
What?
你還好嗎
You good?
我該掛了
Uh, I should probably go.
明天...明天是個大日子
It's a... it's a big day tomorrow.
晚安
Good night.
我們不能接受這樣
We didn't agree to this.
我只知道有兩名情報人員準備就緒
Yeah, well, I was told we had two assets ready to go.
沒有姓名  沒有地點
No names, no places.
時機成熟你們會知道的
You will learn when you need to.
我現在就得知道
I need to know now.
不  我現在就得知道能相信你們
No, I need to know now that I can trust you.
而目前為止  你們說的話不能讓我相信
And so far, nothing you've said is making me think that.
我們要求摩薩德派兩個好手
We asked Mossad for the two best men in Iran.
結果是你們二位
They sent you and you.
他們錯了嗎
Were they wrong?
你需要幫助的暗殺行動  在哪
This assassination you need help-- where?
我還不清楚
I don't know yet.
什么時候
When?
我也不確定  但很快
I'm not sure, but soon.
我們不是這么辦事的  什么都等著看情況
This is not how we work-- everything wait and see.
我跟你們說
I will tell you this.
行動目標是伊朗革命衛隊領袖
The target is the head of the IRGC.
達尼什·阿克巴里嗎
Danesh Akbari?
沒人能接近他
No one can get close to him.
我們能
We can.
他會被就地待命的美國人拿下
He'll be taken down by an American already in place.
我們的工作就是讓他全身而退
Our job is to get that man to safety afterwards.
你們能做到嗎
Can you do that?
他們說不能用槍
They say no gun.
這是氰化物
Is cyanide.
這個  美國人
This, uh, American--
他需要近身阿克巴里
he will need to be right next to Akbari.
而阿克巴里肯定有保鏢護衛
And Akbari will be guarded.
是的  他有貼身衛隊
Yes. He travels with a full security detail.
[波斯語]
我們有C-4炸藥
We have C-4.
我們可以聲東擊西
We can create a diversion.
但這個怎么辦
But what about this?
誰去交給那個美國人
Who will get this to the American?
我來處理
I'll take care of it.
巴吉魯女士嗎
Madame Bezieux?
我是  怎么了
那些人在打聽你
我看就是例行公事
有什么事嗎
這邊請
This way, please.
我們要去哪兒
你們要帶我去哪兒
我沒做錯事
我是貴國游客  有權利知道
安靜  安靜
Quiet! Quiet!
我還是喜歡你金發碧眼的樣子
I liked you better as a blonde.
有必要嗎
Was this really necessary?
你想怎樣  在大堂里喝酒嗎
What do you want, drinks in the lobby?
你讓那個前臺懷疑我了
You've got the desk clerk wondering about me now.
你記住  我根本不想讓你來
Remember, I didn't want you here at all.
任務是阿克巴里
The mission is Akbari.
那才是任務
That's the mission.
你來這兒干嘛  幫布洛迪脫逃
What you're here for, getting Brody out--
大可不必
strictly optional.
可以了嗎
Are we agreed?
任務是阿克巴里  沒錯
The mission is Akbari, yes.
好的
Good.
好
有事發生了
Something happened.
怎么了
What?
阿克巴里白天從不離開辦公室
Akbari never leaves his office during the day.
他說太危險
Too risky, he says.
但他明天要了一支安全車隊
But he's requested a secure convoy for tomorrow.
-他要出門  -去哪兒
- He's heading out. - Where?
沒人會說
No one's saying.
但我昨天告訴他
But I told him yesterday
應該和布洛迪親自談談
that he should really talk to Brody in person.
要開始了
So, it's on?
就用這個嗎
Is that it? The device?
是的
Yeah.
以色列的貨
Israeli.
能交給布洛迪嗎
Can you get it to Brody?
我會想辦法的
I'll find a way.
好了  都聽好
Okay, listen up.
我們在德黑蘭有行動
We have movement in Tehran.
無論如何  我們都希望
We now expect closure on our operation,
這項任務
one way or another
能在當地時間明早9點左右結束
at approximately 9:00 A.M. tomorrow local time.
情報人員認為此次行動會在
Intelligence suggests this will take place
布洛迪被羈押的阿扎迪塔
at a compound near Azadi Tower
附近某建筑進行
where Brody is currently held.
武器  氰化物針
The weapon, a cyanide needle,
正在轉交給他
is being delivered to him,
還有他的撤離計劃
along with the plan for his extraction.
布洛迪的任務是
Brody's job is to position himself
直接和目標達尼什·阿克巴里碰面
in direct contact with the target, Danesh Akbari.
-他怎么通過守衛  -不用
- How does he get past the guards? - He doesn't.
目標來見他
Target comes to him.
最好能私下里會見
We're expecting a personal encounter,
由阿克巴里提出
initiated by Akbari.
我們有兩名摩薩德特工待命
We have two Mossad agents in place,
一個從這棟樓
one with a direct sightline
直接監視樓宇情況
into the compound from this building here.
另一名特工會在布洛迪接近阿克巴里后
That agent will remotely detonate a motorcycle bomb
至少也要在兩人共處一室時
in this alley at a moment
在這條路上
when Brody is proximal to Akbari,
遠程引爆摩托車上的炸彈
at the very least in the same room.
爆炸會造成混亂
The explosion should generate sufficient confusion
使布洛迪干掉目標
to allow Brody to take out the target
并從房子的后門逃走
and escape through this doorway at the rear of the compound.
這里可以直接通向街道
It provides a clear exit to the street
我們的兩名特工會在車里等他
where our two agents will be waiting in a vehicle.
如果計劃順利  布洛迪會在幾小時后
If the rest follows plan, Brody will be delivered
被轉送到德黑蘭外的一所安全屋
to a safe house outside Tehran a few hours later.
有意見嗎
Comments?
我明白  不確定因素還很多
I'm aware-- it's a lot of moving parts.
此次行動卡莉什么角色
Where's Carrie in all this?
她的工作已經完成
She's done her job
整合逃亡計劃
putting together an extraction plan.
行動前不應該讓她撤離嗎
Shouldn't she be pulled out before the event?
她不這么看
She doesn't see it that way.
好了
Okay.
準備吧
Let's get ready.
還剩不到12小時
We have less than 12 hours.
起來  快
Get up. Now!
怎么了
What's going on?
起來把衣服穿上  快點
Get up and get dressed... quickly!
為什么  怎么了
Why? What's happening?
穿這個  快點
In these. Hurry.
我的鞋呢
Where are my shoes?
鞋
Shoes.
給你鞋  快點
Shoes. Hurry.
我覺得他們要出發了
I think they're moving.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他們要帶他走
They are taking him somewhere.
[波斯語]
該死的  你先回來
Shit. Get back here.
索爾  你在看嗎
Saul, are you seeing this?
布洛迪被帶走了
Brody's being moved.
我們看到了
We see it.
他們是帶他去阿克巴里那里嗎
Are they taking him to Akbari?
不  阿克巴里的保鏢隊
No. Akbari's convoy
六分鐘前就離開了伊革命衛隊
left the IRGC six minutes ago.
我們還以為是去你那里
We thought he was coming to you.
所以布洛迪他媽的是要去哪里
So where the fuck is Brody going?
我們得跟上他們
Hey, we need to follow them.
你們派的刺客居然是尼古拉斯·布洛迪
Your assassin is Nicholas Brody?
對  我們能開始行動了嗎
Yes. Can we get moving?
他可是世界頭號通緝犯
The most wanted man in the world.
這么重要的事居然不告訴我們
This was not important for us to know?
那現在你知道了
Well, now you know.
我們走吧
Let's go.
快走吧
注意這里
Look at this.
阿克巴里和布洛迪的車隊正在靠攏
Akbari. Brody. The convoys are converging.
朝哪里靠攏
Converging where?
一個叫達瓦吉噶爾的地方
An area called Darvazy Gar.
阿克巴里的車停下了
Akbari's stopping.
他的人封鎖了那個地方
His men are locking down the area.
他們在羅斯塔米街
They're on Rostami Street.
卡莉在哪里
Where's Carrie?
布洛迪后面兩個街區
Two blocks behind Brody.
這是什么地方
What is this place?
馬上就到了
Almost there.
阿克巴里進了那棟樓
Akbari's gone inside that house.
查出住戶的身份
Find out who lives there.
我們正在查
Yeah. We're looking.
別忙著找  問一下賈瓦迪
Don't just look. Ask Javadi.
地址是羅斯塔米街421號
The address is 421 Rostami Street.
卡莉
Carrie,
阿克巴里和布洛迪在你前方90米處
Akbari and Brody are 100 yards ahead of you.
會面開始了
Meeting is on.
在這里停
Stop here.
停  快停下
Stop! Stop.
這不是個好主意  我們毫無準備
This is not a good idea. We are not set up.
我們有準備  布洛迪見到了阿克巴里
We are. Brody's meeting Akbari.
唯一有變化的是地點
The only thing that's changed is the location.
布洛迪知道我們在這里嗎
Does Brody even know we are here?
他聽到爆炸聲就會知道了
As soon as he hears the explosion, he'll know.
優素福現在需要找個地方
Yousef needs to find a place now.
我們現在最好暫時收手
The best thing is for us to back away,
等待一個更好的機會
wait for a better chance.
不會再有更好的機會了  你搞清楚這點
There won't be a better chance, do you understand?
只管照做
Just do it.
優素福
Yousef...
[波斯語]
牽制炸彈裝好了
Diversion is set.
卡莉  你來指揮
Your call, Carrie.
你有現場指揮的便利
You're the eyes on the ground.
優素福
Yousef...
[波斯語]
這操他娘的發生了什么事
The fuck what is happening?
阿克巴里離開了
Akbari's leaving.
他們根本沒有碰面  阿克巴里走了
They never met. Akbari's gone.
我想他是要進那棟樓里去
I think he's going inside the house.
我他媽的最后問一遍
For the last fucking time,
我們能不能查到是誰住在那里
can we find out who lives there?
[波斯語]
尼古拉斯
Nicholas.
索爾  賈瓦迪的消息
Saul, a message from Javadi:
羅斯塔米街421號屬于伊革命衛隊
421 Rostami is owned by the IRGC.
現在的住戶叫納塞林·莫勒彼
Current resident... Nassrin Mughrabi.
卡莉  布洛迪見的是納塞林·莫勒彼
Carrie, Brody is meeting with Nassrin Mughrabi.
納塞林  那是誰
Nassrin? Who is that?
阿布·納齊爾的遺孀
Abu Nazir's widow.
阿克巴里為什么要這么做
Why did Akbari do this?
布洛迪曾在納塞林家住過兩年
Brody lived in Nassrin's house for two years.
阿克巴里用她來審查布洛迪
Akbari's using her to vet Brody.
阿克巴里告訴我你在這里的時候
When Akbari told me you were here,
我根本不敢相信
I couldn't believe it.
但是你還是出現了
But here you are.
我的尼古拉斯
My Nicholas.
我完全沒想到你會住在德黑蘭
I had no idea you were living in Tehran.
納齊爾死后我一直住這里
It's been my home since Nazir died.
我很抱歉  納塞林
I'm sorry, Nassrin.
再沒有人能像他一樣了
There was no one like him.
再也沒有了
No one.
看得出來你經歷了很多
But I can see you have been through a lot.
我上次見你的時候
When I last saw you,
你像個就要上戰場的士兵
you were like a soldier going to war.
我現在是從戰場歸來的士兵
Now I'm a soldier back from war.
得勝歸來
With a victory.
根本算不上什么勝利
It's hard to see it like that.
我失去了那么多
I lost so much.
你的家人
Your family.
尤其是我的女兒
My daughter, especially.
當我...
When I, um...
當我完成任務
when I completed the... the plan that, um,
安拉交付我的使命
Allah had set out for me...
這擊垮了她
it destroyed her.
她試圖自殺
She tried to kill herself.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
信念的缺失讓人迷茫
It is hard when you don't have faith.
她有信念
She had faith.
她相信她的父親不會背叛她
She had faith that her own father wouldn't betray her
讓她生不如死
and make her life unlivable.
納齊爾幫你做好了思想準備
Nazir prepared you for this.
他說只要你忠于安拉
He said that if you were true to Allah,
你會心如止水
you would find peace.
你是虔誠的
And you were true.
你也是
And so were you.
你心如止水了嗎
Have you found peace?
有時能
Sometimes... yes.
但有時我會問
But sometimes I ask
為什么真主要帶走我的兒子
why God had to take my son
和丈夫  而留下我
and my husband instead of me,
然后我的感覺和你女兒一樣
and then I feel like your daughter did:
生不如死
life is unlivable.
但我挺過來了
But I survive.
我們都應該這樣
It's what we do.
對
Yes.
我們掙脫苦海
We crawl out of the rubble
重新振作
and we gather up the bodies.
你為什么來德黑蘭  尼古拉斯
Why did you come to Tehran, Nicholas?
我無處可去
I had nowhere else.
你來這里干什么
What do you want here?
我想結束逃亡
I want to stop running.
你在這里干什么
What are you doing here?
[波斯語]
告訴我們你在這里干什么
Tell us what you are doing here.
你在這里干什么
What... what are you doing here?
蒙主恩澤
By the grace of God...
我來這里尋求庇護
I am here to seek asylum.
只有在這里  我才能心如止水
This is the only place in the world that I can find peace.
你是德黑蘭的名人了  布洛迪
You're a big man in Tehran, Brody.
真正的大人物
A really big man now.
六天后
在你那段著名的錄像里  你說
In your famous videotape, you said,
我愛我的祖國
"I love my country."
我是真心的
Which I meant.
但美國卻把你列為國家公敵
And yet America declares you an enemy of the state.
美國人的自我標榜與現實的美國
There's a wide gulf between what America says it is
是天壤之別
and what it actually is.
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
最新的羞辱
The most recent insult.
這是否能解釋你12月12日的行動
Does this explain your actions on December 12?
是的
It does.
對
Yes.
[波斯語]
布洛迪在一周內學了波斯語
Brody learned enough Farsi in one week
為了在國家電視節目中譴責我們
to denounce us on state television.
標準的"美國去死"論調
Standard "Death to America" fare.
[波斯語]
但我聽說他的移送過程很順利
But I'm told his delivery is pitch-perfect.
剛剛和他通過電話
Just got off the phone with him.
他要求"行動"
He demanded "Action."
沒錯
Yeah.
我接到了相同的電話
I got the same call.
布洛迪這部分行動
The Brody part of the operation
總是很艱難  索爾
was always a long shot, Saul.
所有部分都很難
It was all a long shot.
行動奏效了
And it worked,
在此之前
until now.
布洛迪不可能接近阿克巴里
Brody's never going to get anywhere near Akbari.
我知道
I know.
賈瓦迪的直接消息
That's straight from Javadi.
布洛迪已經被伊朗公關部接手
Brody's been handed off to their PR department.
我們沒有機會了
Our window is closed.
那我們要放棄他嗎
So we just discard him?
我們想讓他撤離
We tried to extract him.
但布洛迪沒有在集合點露面
Brody didn't even show up for the rendezvous.
現在他在整個德黑蘭大放厥詞
Now he's spouting off all over Tehran.
最起碼
Bottom line,
布洛迪從線人變成了大累贅
Brody's gone from asset to serious liability.
我得知道他怎么想的
I need to know what he's thinking.
他的想法顯而易見
It's obvious what he's thinking:
就是他在那些網絡視頻中說的話
what he's saying on all those YouTube videos.
伊朗救了他
Iran saved his life,
他熱愛伊朗  憎恨美國
he loves them, hates us.
你知道還有什么嗎
And you know what else?
無論他現在腦子里想些什么
Whatever he's thinking today,
誰能確保在今后不會變成現實
who's to say what it will be tomorrow?
他和當初將他洗腦的同一撥人
He's spending his days with the same people
生活在一起
who brainwashed him in the first place,
對于布洛迪可以確認的一點
and one thing we know about Brody is
就是這個家伙反復無常
this is a guy who changes his mind.
你在伊革命衛隊中安插了重要線人
You placed a major asset inside the IRGC.
馬吉德·賈瓦迪
Majid Javadi.
這是值得我們繼續利用的重大勝利
That's a huge victory worth preserving.
布洛迪隨時會暴露賈瓦迪的身份
Brody could expose him at any moment,
事情很簡單
and the simple fact is
我們不能信任布洛迪
we can't trust Brody.
不能信任
We never could.
該結束了
We need to end it.
你是說殺了布洛迪嗎
You mean end Brody?
總統希望能解決此問題
The president wants this resolved.
我們知道布洛迪每日做禱告的地方
We know where Brody prays every day.
摩薩德在那邊也有人
Mossad has some men on the ground there.
是時候了
It's time.
他當然要抨擊我們
Of course he's bad-mouthing us.
你指望他說什么
What do you expect?
只有這樣  他才能不被懷疑  索爾
He's doing what he needs to, to preserve his cover, Saul.
僅此而已
That's all.
冷靜下  我只是問問
Well, calm down. I'm just asking.
計劃有變
The plan changed,
按照我們通常的做法
so we do what we always do,
我們隨機應變
what he's doing-- we adjust.
我們應變過了
We did adjust.
我們試圖讓他撤走
We tried lifting him out of there.
他沒理會
He blew us off.
那是因為他覺得原計劃能成功
Because he still thinks the plan can work.
這是他的原話嗎
Is that what he's saying?
這是我的話
That's what I'm saying.
所以  他還沒和你聯系嗎
So he hasn't reached out to you?
沒有  我們一直都說  和我聯系
No. We said all along any contact with me
風險太大  不是嗎
was too risky, right?
發生什么事了
What's going on?
你是時候該回來了
It's time you got on a plane and came back.
我們不能就這么把他丟在這里
We can't just abandon him here.
索爾  從始至終我對他的判斷都是正確的
Saul, I have been right about him this whole time.
我知道
I know.
等你回來了  我們再好好談
And we'll talk it through when you're back.
卡莉
Carrie?
卡莉  聽得到嗎
Carrie, you hear me?
聽得到
Yeah, sure.
再見
Bye.
拜
她才不會乖乖地坐上飛機
She's not getting on any plane.
我知道
I know.
我們來解決吧
Let's get it done.
現在就去
Do it now.
馬蘇德  我是卡莉
Masud. It's Carrie.
你得再幫我一次
I need one more favor.
日安
Salaam.
[波斯語]
有個朋友待會兒會給你打電話
A friend will call you now.
[波斯語]
請你在里面等我一會兒
Will you wait inside for me a moment, please?
謝謝
Thank you.
你好
Yes?
是我  我就站在庭院對面
It's me. I'm across the courtyard.
布洛迪  我有車
Brody, I have a car.
我得把你帶離德黑蘭
I need to get you out of Tehran.
我跟他們說過了  我不走
I told them already, I don't want to leave.
我知道  你的話讓他們覺得不安
I know, and it made them nervous.
不安  這什么意思
Nervous? What's that mean?
我也不清楚
I'm not sure.
沒人肯告訴我  我猜他們打算...
No one would tell me, but I think they're...
丟卒保車  以保護賈瓦迪
they're cutting their losses to protect Javadi.
丟卒保車
Cutting their losses?
我說過了  還不確定
I said I'm not sure.
是指我嗎
Meaning me?
那是他
That's him.
他似乎在打電話
Looks like he's on the phone.
摩薩德的人在哪
Where's Mossad?
拜托  和我一起  坐上車就好
Please, just come with me, just get in the car.
去哪
And go where?
哪都行  求你了
Anywhere. Please.
求你  現在就跟我走
Please, just come with me now.
一旦出了德黑蘭  我們就能重整旗鼓
As soon as we're clear of Tehran, we can regroup.
還重整旗鼓個屁
Regroup for what?
再做個操蛋的計劃嗎
What? To make another fucked-up plan?
不是  我們得離開
No, we just need to leave.
別這么說  行嗎
Will you stop saying that?
離開  離開  去哪啊
Leave, leave. Leave where?
我無處可去  卡莉
I have nowhere to go, Carrie!
我不可能回美國了
I can't go back to the States.
那我們去別的地方
We'll go somewhere else.
做什么呢
And do what?
四處躲藏嗎
Hide out?
然后他們追捕我們倆嗎
So they're hunting us both?
我有人脈
I have contacts.
我已經經歷過一次了  卡莉
I've been through that already, Carrie.
不想再來一次了
I won't do it again.
我也不會讓你承受一次的
And I won't do it to you.
雙人組在那里
And there's the Tag Team.
布洛迪  求你了
Brody, please.
見鬼
Shit.
已經開始了
It's happening.
什么事
What?
你背后  從清真寺走過來的兩個男人
Behind you, from the mosque, there's two men,
一個穿著深色襯衫和卡其色褲子
one in a dark shirt and khaki pants,
另一個穿著皮夾克
the other in leather jacket.
別掛電話
Just stay on the phone
我會告訴你情況
and I will talk you through.
他在移動
He's moving.
-布洛迪  -快離開這里
- Brody? - Just get out of here.
有人提醒了他
Someone warned him.
誰干的
Who?
她真是狗膽包天
She wouldn't fucking dare.
怎么的
What?
你這事干得真操蛋
You really fucked up this time.
他是為我們工作的
He's working for us.
那個計劃失敗了
The plan failed.
所以你就派來人來殺他
So you send a hit squad?
我們試圖把他召回  被他拒絕了
We tried to recall him. He said no.
現在托你的福  他可以在德黑蘭
Now thanks to you, he's loose
街上自由行動  天知道他會干什么
on the streets of Tehran doing God knows what.
日安
Salaam.
日安  日安
Salaam, salaam.
[阿拉伯語]
拜托  告訴她
Please, tell her.
馬上告訴她  這非常重要
Tell her right now. It's very important.
尼古拉斯
Nicholas?
我沒想到你會來
I wasn't expecting you.
對不起
I'm sorry.
納塞林  我需要你的幫助
Nassrin, I need your help.
發生什么事了
What happened?
你還好嗎
Are you all right?
有人想殺我
Somebody just tried to kill me.
我的天
My God.
我得和達尼什·阿克巴里談談
I need to talk to Danesh Akbari.
達尼什
Danesh...
他可不喜歡被人打擾
he is a very private man.
我有...
I have...
我有關于馬吉德·賈瓦迪的消息
I have information about Majid Javadi
絕對是他需要知道的
that he absolutely needs to know, okay?
這非常重要
It's very important.
求你了  納塞林  求你
Please, Nassrin, please, okay?
好吧  好吧  我會告訴他的
All right, all right, I'll tell him.
我們從賈瓦迪那里收到一條消息
We got a message from Javadi.
布洛迪剛剛在革命衛隊總部現身了
Brody just showed up at the Revolutionary Guard headquarters.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
賈瓦迪說護送他的人是阿克巴里的手下
Javadi said he was escorted by Akbari's men.
他要去見阿克巴里
He's going to Akbari.
布洛迪知道我們想殺他
Brody knows we just tried to kill him.
他會讓整個計劃全他媽泡湯
He's gonna burn the whole fucking thing down.
納塞林告訴我你很激動
Nassrin told me you were upset.
想找我談談
That you wanted to talk to me.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
你知道嗎  我就是在這間辦公室
You know, it was here in this office
第一次聽說你的名字
that I first heard your name.
阿布·納齊爾跟我談起過你
Abu Nazir told me about you:
他找到了怎樣的一塊寶石
what a jewel he had found...
怎樣的一把真主之劍
what a sword for Allah.
怎么會有人...
Why would anyone...
想要殺掉這樣一件珍寶
want to kill such a treasure?
是想阻止我告訴你關于賈瓦迪的事情
To stop me telling you about Javadi.
賈瓦迪的什么事
What about Javadi?
他覬覦你的職位
He wants your job.
你以為我會不知道嗎
You think I don't know that?
中情局已經為他計劃好了
The CIA has planned it for him.
中情局
The CIA?
就算是賈瓦迪這樣的人也不會和中情局合作的
Even Javadi wouldn't work with the CIA.
可他合作了
Well, he is.
他們發現他挪用了革命衛隊幾百萬的公款
They found out he embezzled millions from the IRGC.
他們握住了他的把柄
They own him.
你是在逃犯
You were on the run.
你怎么會知道美國方面在做些什么
How could you know what the Americans are doing?
因為這個計劃我也有份
Because I was part of it.
我來到德黑蘭是為了接近你
I was to come here to Tehran to get close to you.
你接近我以后要干什么
And when you got close?
他們想讓我把你除掉...
They wanted me to take you out...
以便讓賈瓦迪取代你
...so they could replace you with Javadi.
那就是我接到的指令
Those were my orders.
不過你并不想執行這些指令
But you don't want to obey those orders.
所以你才會來找我
That's why you came to me.
我來這里是為了自我救贖
I came here to redeem myself.
你已經做到了
And you have.
已經做到了
You have.
謝謝你  尼古拉斯
Thank you, Nicholas.
我會對付賈瓦迪的
I will deal with Javadi.
你和阿布·納齊爾談起過我嗎
You spoke with Abu Nazir about me?
就在這個房間嗎
In this room?
是的
Yes.
談起他是如何派你去對抗美國的
How he would send you against America.
就像一把插入敵人心臟的利劍
A sword to strike the heart of our enemy.
很好
Good.
都是在這里開始的
It all started here.
喂
Yes?
是我
It's me.
我在阿克巴里的辦公室
I'm in Akbari's office.
布洛迪  你做了什么
Brody, what have you done?
我把他殺了
I killed him.
把我弄出去
Get me out of here.